TINASHE GARAPASI

+263773636256 | 0292-523279 | t.garapass@gmail.com | Bulawayo, Zimbabwe Quantity Surveyor | Estimator | Data Analytics

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A male actively seeking for a quantity surveying placement to improve my skills and expand my industrial knowledge and make a positive contribution to the organization. As a Quantity Surveyor and Estimator, have accumulated 3 years in contracting, and have engaged in freelance contracting for 4 years, specializing in tender submissions, project evaluation, and cost reporting. Further accumulated extensive skills in data analysis and research.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance: Estimation | Quantity Surveying | Monitoring & Evaluation

02/2021 - Present

- Participated in tender submission for 60 Ablution Blocks projects managed by Simphiwe Trust (NGO), overseeing a project valued at US\$150,000.00 to enhance community sanitation infrastructure.
- Developed a monitoring & evaluation framework for climate-friendly structures post-Cyclone Idai, supporting rehabilitation efforts for houses with a local NGO (Mai Nevana).
- Quantified multiple residential and commercial structures, with a collective value of US\$500,000.00 in value, ensuring accurate cost estimation and budget compliance.

Quantity Surveyor, Mangqoba Engineers & Contractors (MEC)

02/2019 - 10/2021

- Conducted comprehensive Building and Site surveys to assess project scope and feasibility.
- Quantified quantities, created rate build up structures, with the goal of managing construction costs.
- Conducted quality assurance inspections and monitored maintenance and repair services to uphold project standards and minimize downtime.

Intern Quantity Surveyor (National Diploma), National Railways of Zimbabwe (NRZ) 02/2016 - 12/2017

Conducted site surveys, production of BoQs and other duties as a Quantity Surveyor intern

EDUCATION

- National Certificate in Quantity Surveying, Bulawayo Polytechnic, 2014
- National Diploma in Quantity Surveying, Bulawayo Polytechnic, 2018
- Bachelor of Science Honours in Quantity Surveying, (NUST) 2022 Ongoing

SKILLS AND PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

- Certificate in Construction Health and Safety OSHA Academy
- Estimation and Billing using WinQS, and Microsoft Excel
- Basic drawing using ArchiCAD
- Data analysis, research, visualization and report writing using SPSS, Ms Word, Ms Excel and Microsoft Project
- Presentations using PowerPoint.
- Mapping, site surveying and extraction of data using Quantum GIS,
- Driver's license Class 2

VOLUNTEER WORK

Active in helping SMEs in producing business plans and provision of data collection and research services

MENTOR

Freedom Ndebele - Contracts Manager/ Senior Quantity Surveyor, fritz.ndebele.qs@gmail.com

REFERENCES

Available on Request